<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Wodin News</title><link>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/</link><description>Recent content on Wodin News</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 17:10:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lots of small interface tweaks</title><link>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/wodin-0-2-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 17:10:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/wodin-0-2-0/</guid><description>While working towards getting stochastic models running, we&amp;rsquo;ve made a number of relatively smaller interface improvements that smooth over a number of rough edges.
Sum of squares is now shown in the Run tab if you have a &amp;ldquo;fitting&amp;rdquo; app and it is possible to compute it All plots have x axis labels; these show Time for plots over time, and the parameter being varied in the other sensitivity plots Sensitivity will not lock up the browser as badly if the model run is slow, and will display progressively as it computes each iteration Long labels are not truncated, particularly in the sensitivity plots It is possible to display plots with a log-y axis (this setting will be automatically shared across all plot types and saved with the session) A slightly nicer workflow for creating a new session based on the contents of your current saved session</description></item><item><title>Demo Site</title><link>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/demo-site/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 11:18:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/demo-site/</guid><description>We have added a new demo site to the epimodels deployment at epimodels.dide.ic.ac.uk/demo which shows off the main features of Wodin and information on configuration; you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to refer to this when building a site. The underlying source repo may be a useful resource when building a deployment too.</description></item><item><title>Initial release</title><link>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/initial-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 13:51:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/initial-release/</guid><description>We have made the initial release of Wodin, with the basic app running the first practical for the MSc course 🎉
This is the result of more than half a year&amp;rsquo;s work, porting over the functionality from our original initial Shiny application, initially developed for the 2019 Mathematical Models of the Epidemiology &amp;amp; Control of Infectious Diseases short course but since showing its age.
With this version, we support creation of simple ODE models, exploring these models with interactive graphs, investigating sensitivity to changes in parameters and fitting models to data using least squares.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/about/</guid><description>Wodin is odin on the web, an application that compiles the odin domain specific language for differential equations into JavaScript and allows exploration of dynamical systems without installing any software at all. It has been built by us at RESIDE to support teaching activities within the MRC Centre for Global Infectious Disease Analysis
It is composed of many moving parts
wodin, an express-based API and TypeScript/Vue.js based web application odin.api, a porcelain/plumber API which interfaces between wodin and odin odin, a domain specific language (DSL) for expressing systems differential equations odin-js, JavaScript support code for running odin models in JavaScript dopri-js, a differential equation solver written in TypeScript</description></item></channel></rss>