<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Feature on Wodin News</title><link>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/tags/feature/</link><description>Recent content in Feature on Wodin News</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 09:35:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/tags/feature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hide Variables</title><link>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/hide-variables/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 09:35:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/hide-variables/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re working on a complex model there are often variables that need to exist in the model that are needed to solve your model, but are not that interesting. Worse - sometimes these variables make your graph unreadable because they&amp;rsquo;re on a really different scale (e.g., the number of susceptible individuals in a disease that never reaches a very high level in a population).
As of wodin 0.3.0, you can now select variables to show from below the editor, on the Code tab:</description></item><item><title>Initial release</title><link>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/initial-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 13:51:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://reside-ic.github.io/wodin-news/posts/initial-release/</guid><description>We have made the initial release of Wodin, with the basic app running the first practical for the MSc course 🎉
This is the result of more than half a year&amp;rsquo;s work, porting over the functionality from our original initial Shiny application, initially developed for the 2019 Mathematical Models of the Epidemiology &amp;amp; Control of Infectious Diseases short course but since showing its age.
With this version, we support creation of simple ODE models, exploring these models with interactive graphs, investigating sensitivity to changes in parameters and fitting models to data using least squares.</description></item></channel></rss>